# Elias Rubin

17 West Mercer #3, Seattle, WA, 98119 erubin@princeton.edu | 907.230.8330

## **OBJECTIVE**

I am a junior at Princeton University studying Astrophysics and pursuing a certificate in Statistics and Machine Learning. I am at my best and happiest when solving problems and am interested in an internship for the summer of 2016. I have a rigorous scientific and quantitative background as well as substantial research experience and am most interested in working in technology.

## **EDUCATION**

## PRINCETON UNIVERSITY

#### A.B, ASTROPHYSICS

Expected May 2017 | Princeton, NJ GPA: 3.3 | Departmental GPA: 3.6 Certificate in Statistics and Machine Learning

#### Coursework

Probability and Stochastic Systems Computational Physics Seminar General Computer Science General Relativity Stars and Star Formation Research Methods in Astrophysics Quantum Mechanics Thermal Physics Mechanics and Waves Intermediate Swahili

## **WEST ANCHORAGE HS**

Grad. May 2013 | Anchorage, AK SUMMA CUM LAUDE

National AP Scholar, National Merit Finalist

SAT: Critical Reading - 800, Writing - 800, Math - 760

## SKILLS

## **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

Python

C

Java

Julia

## **SOFTWARE AND TOOLS**

Unix and Mac OS X LaTeX Git

Microsoft Office

## **EXPERIENCE**

## PRINCETON UNIVERSITY DEPARTMENT OF ASTROPHYSICS

#### SUMMER RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

June 2015 - August 2015 | Princeton, NJ

- Worked with faculty and research staff to model radiation feedback effects in giant molecular clouds using massively parallel radiation hydrodynamics simulations on a variety of architectures.
- Added additional physics to and wrote new simulation code for the *Athena* MHD modeling software in C.
- Managed and analyzed large amounts of simulation data using Python.

## **ANCHORAGE JUNIOR NORDIC LEAGUE**

#### COACH

January 2012 - March 2013 | Anchorage, AK

- Instructed children ages 6-9 in cross-country skiing.
- Independently managed a group of between four and twelve skiers with various levels of experience and fitness.

## **ACTIVITIES AND SERVICE**

## OUTDOOR ACTION PROGRAM | LEADER & TECHNICAL SKILLS

**TRAINER** 

2014 - Present | Princeton, NJ

- Led a multiday wilderness backpacking orientation trip for first-year students.
- Continued to serve as a peer resource to first-year students throughout the academic year.
- Taught underclassmen interested in becoming Outdoor Action leaders technical wilderness skills and Leave No Trace principles.
- Led refresher classes for Outdoor Action Leaders before their orientation trips.
- Contributed to development of technical skills and Leave No Trace curriculum.

## SANS COMIC SKETCH COMEDY | WRITING DIRECTOR

2015 - Present | Princeton, NJ

- Cofounded a new sketch comedy group at Princeton.
- Wrote several sketches and helped other writers develop their material.
- Planned and executed long term strategy for the group.

## MWENGE ENGLISH SCHOOL | ENGLISH TEACHER

June 2014 - August 2014 | Dar es Salaam, Tanzania

• Taught English in individual and group lessons to adult learners with varying levels of experience.